Sarah Ann Garcia

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Full stack web developer that is proficient in React, Typescript, NodeJS, NextJS, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SQL Databases, and Domain Driven Design as well as experience in jQuery, MeteorJS, Python, Mongo Databases, and Aurelia. Also a Mechanical Engineer with 3.5 years of industry experience.

Relevant Employment History

Software Engineer, Quickdraw Development, Remote

Nov. 2018 - May 2020; Sept. 2021 - May 2023

- Build and design front-end web applications in React for a variety of industries
- Built three APIs using Domain Driven Design (DDD)
- · Utilized pug for dynamic PDF creation
- Modify existing websites to add new features or debug existing features
- Work through sprint cycles, client beta testing, and post launch bugs
- Scrum Master for development team (planning sprints, ensuring projects are on track, building road-maps for product development, and designing features)

Lead Frontend Web Developer, Kayhan Space, Remote

May 2020 — SEPT. 2021

- Created readable information for satellite operators through designing and building a satellite monitoring web application using React, Redux, Node.js, PostgresSQL, and more
- Utilized Scrum methodology when creating the product road map to plan sprints
- · Articulated sprint goals to team members through regular meetings
- Built frontend web application and accompanying API using designs and specifications created with leadership team
- Crafted policy documents to outline best practices for component development and testing for primary user-facing application and supporting API
- Interact and coordinate with three additional teams to ensure all APIs communicate efficiently

Education

Full Stack Web Developer, Web Development, Thinkful: Full Stack & Data Science, Remote

AUGUST 2017 — JUNE 2018

BS, Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta

August 2010 — May 2013

Details

Georgia, United States
706.593.2517
sarahanngarcia30@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio LinkedIn Github

Skills

React

Typescript

NodeJS

NextJS

Javascript

HTML5 & CSS3

Domain Driven Design

Git

SQL Databases

Mongo Databases

jQuery

Aurelia

Python

Angular

PHP